(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-15T22:40:05.264311",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.6-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
ろーぼ飯店へようこそ
Welcome to Ro-bo Restaurant
withØ
君の心の中を全部見せてよ
Show me everything inside your heart.
何が好きで何が嫌いで 僕はどのくらいかな？
What do you like, what do you hate, and where do I stand?
今日はどんな服着て
What clothes are you wearing today,
どこで何をしてるの？
where are you, and what are you doing?
嘘を全部隠さないでいいよ 僕に教えて
You don't have to hide any lies, just tell me.
偏見なんて気にしない
I don't care about prejudices.
先入観ばっか くだらない
Nothing but preconceptions—how silly.
期待しないなんて嘘ばかり
Saying "I don't expect anything" is all a lie.
顔色伺う毎日に
In everyday life spent reading the room,
一人で踊ればいい
I might as well dance alone.
眠れない
Can't sleep
ずっと知らなかった言葉も
Even words I never knew before,
しらふのままじゃ出てこないなら
if I can't say them while sober,
三つ数えて
count to three,
世界が止まればいいのに
if only the world would stop.
触れ溶け合うくらいの距離感で
At a distance close enough to touch and melt into each other,
僕のことだけ見ててよ
look only at me,
跡つけてよ
leave your mark on me,
消えないくらいに ほらね
so it won't fade. See?
今 ぎゅってして
Hold me tight now.
曖昧だっていいよなんて 僕はわかるから
Because I understand if you say ambiguity is fine,
気づかないふりしてあげるってだからね
so I'll pretend not to notice.
今 好きって言ってよ
Tell me you love me right now.
好きって言ってよ
Tell me you love me.
永遠なんてありはしない
Eternity doesn't exist,
健全なんて予想ばかり
soundness is nothing but expectations.
期待したいなんて高上がり
Expecting too much from expectations,
顔色窺いもギリギリ
reading the room is at its limit.
一人で泣けばいい
It's fine to cry alone,
でも一人じゃ笑えない
but I can't laugh alone.
ずっと知らなかった言葉も
Even words I never knew before,
表のままじゃ出てこないんだ
won't come out if kept on the surface.
三つ数えて
Count to three,
世界が変わればいいのに
if only the world would change.
ガラガラと音を立てていく
Making a rattling sound,
崩れる景色の中 落ちていく
falling into the crumbling scenery.
見つけ出してよ
Find me,
離れないくらいに ほらね
so close that we won't part. See?
今 ぎゅってして
Hold me tight now.
何回だっていいよなんて 僕はわかるから
Because I understand even if you say any number of times is fine,
いつか最後に許してくれるってだからね
so eventually in the end you'll forgive me.
また 好きって言ってよ
Tell me you love me again.
夜が明けるまで話を聞いて
Listen to me until night breaks,
終わらない夢みたいに輝いて見えた
shining like an endless dream.
どうか今だけ覚まさないで
Please don't wake me up, just for now.
冗談じゃないよ
It's no joke,
君のいない明日なんて全部いらない
I don't need a tomorrow without you at all.
ずっと一緒だよね
We'll be together forever, right?
触れ溶け合うくらいの距離感で
At a distance close enough to touch and melt into each other,
僕のことだけ見ててよ
look only at me,
跡つけてよ 消えないくらいに
leave your mark on me so it won't fade.
ほらね 今 ぎゅってして
See? Hold me tight now.
何回だっていいよなんて 僕はわかるから
Because I understand even if you say any number of times is fine,
気づかないふりしてあげるってだからね
so I'll pretend not to notice.
今 好きって言ってよ
Tell me you love me right now.
好きって言ってよ
Tell me you love me.
ないない
No, no,
深い影ばかり
nothing but deep shadows.
愛のない
Lacking love,
答え
an answer.
ドールみたい
Like a doll,
自分不在
devoid of self,
どこにもいない
nowhere to be found.
ない じゃない
Isn't that right?
曖昧な愛
Vague love,
色のない愛
colorless love.
期待 以外
Anything but expectations,
人事みたい
like someone else's business.
おかげさま
Thanks to you,
どちら様
who might you be?
応え様々
Various answers.
何者でもないまま
Remaining a nobody,
何にもできないまま
unable to do anything.
生きるの無駄ですが
Living is pointlessly futile, but...
悪いことですか
Is that such a bad thing?
ここにいない いない いないのは
The one who isn't here, isn't here, isn't here
自分 自分
is myself, myself.
誰も見ない 見ない 見ないまま
Without anyone looking, looking, looking,
吐き捨ててサヨナラ
spitting it out and saying goodbye.
嬉しくない
I'm not happy,
悲しくもない
nor am I sad,
透明な気分
a transparent feeling.
足りない自分
An inadequate self,
合わす顔もない
ashamed to show my face.
ない
There is none,
笑えないじゃない
can't even laugh, right?
「はい」じゃない
It's not "yes,"
「いいえ」じゃない
it's not "no."
閉じたままかい
Is it kept closed?
期待だけかい
Is it only expectations?
イヤイヤ投げられた賽
Reluctantly cast dice,
てめえは知らねえ
you don't know a thing.
居たい 居たい 居たいのは
The one who wants to stay, stay, stay
自分 自分
is myself, myself.
味わい苦い 苦い 苦い
The taste is bitter, bitter, bitter,
ないいまも
Even now, no...
あてはなく さようなら
Aimlessly, goodbye.
帰れない 行く先もないまま
Unable to go back, with nowhere to go.
迷い子の傷 間違えてない
A lost child's wounds, not mistaken.
まだわからない
I still don't know.
ない どうだっていいじゃない
Nothing... Doesn't it matter anyway?
どんなストーリーだって どんなストーリーだって
No matter what kind of story, no matter what kind of story,
どんなストーリーになったってファイナル
Whatever story it becomes, it's the final.
影も形もいっそ失くしてしまえばいい
It'd be better to lose both shadow and shape entirely.
またひとつひとつから始めればいい
Starting anew one by one would be fine.
ここにいないいないいないのは 自分 自分
The one who isn't, isn't, isn't here is myself, myself.
誰も見ない見ない見ないまま 投げ捨ててさようなら
Without anyone looking, looking, looking, throwing it away, goodbye.
嬉しくない 悲しくもない
Not happy, nor sad.
透明な気分
A transparent mood.
足りない自分 合わせる顔もない
My lacking self has no face to show.
ない
Nothing...
ない ないままで
Remaining as nothing, nothing...
ここにいたい いたい
I want to stay here, stay here.
笑いたいじゃない
Don't I want to laugh?
(Lalala...)
(Chorus vocalizing)
はーい！ということで来てくれてありがとー！
Alright! So thank you so much for coming!
改めて、ホロライブ所属0期生バーチャルロボットVTuberのロボ子だよー！
Once again, I'm Roboco, a Gen 0 virtual robot VTuber from Hololive!
今日は僕の誕生日ライブに来てくれてありがとうー！
Thank you for coming to my birthday live today!
もう「高性能？」みたいなコメント拾わないからね！
I won't pick up comments like "High performance?" anymore, okay!
だって僕今日9歳！主役！あ、やべ、誕生日のお祝い質問しようと思ったのに言っちゃった！
Because today I'm 9 years old! The star! Ah shoot, I was gonna ask a birthday question, but I spilled it!
はい！そう、ロボなんと今年で9歳になりましたー！9歳ー！
Yes! That's right, Robo has turned 9 years old this year! 9 years old!
ヤバない？来年もう2桁になる。ヤバい、ヤバすぎる！
Isn't that crazy? Next year I'll already be in double digits. Crazy, way too crazy!
ワクワクしてきた！最後の1桁楽しんでいきたいと思います！
I'm getting excited! I want to enjoy my last single-digit year!
はい！ということで、本日のハッシュタグをご紹介します！
Alright! So now let me introduce today's hashtag!
じょじょん！本日のハッシュタグは...あ、こっちだった！#ロボ子爆誕2025 ですね！皆さん見えましたか？
Ta-da! Today's hashtag is... Ah, it was this way! #RobokoBakutan2025! Could everyone see it?
きっと高性能な君たちだったら、もう #ロボ子爆誕2025 をつけて呟いていることでしょう！はい！
Since you guys are high-performance, I'm sure you're already tweeting with #RobokoBakutan2025! Yes!
たくさん僕の可愛いスクショとともに、投稿していってくださいね！
Please post lots of tweets along with cute screenshots of me!
こうして人は循環していくんですよ！投稿っ！
This is how people circulate! Keep posting!
はい！ということで、まずは今日はね、僕のオリジナル曲「With Love」から始まって「ないない」を歌ったんですけど、どうでしたか？
Alright! So first today, we started with my original song "With Love" and then I sang "Nai Nai", how was it?
「With Love」はMVと同じね、ウルフレイヤーじゃなくて通常の強そうなロングのやつで巻き巻きで行ったんですけれど、どうだった？よかった？
For "With Love", I went with my usual strong-looking curled long hair instead of the wolf layer like in the MV, but how was it? Was it good?
え、なんかもう久しぶりだよね？このナイティドレスとかも。ウルフレイヤーになって初めてなんじゃない？
It's been a while, right? With this nightdress too. Isn't this the first time since getting the wolf layer cut?
ショートカット...ショート動画でしか撮らないからね。そう、セクシーでしょ？
Because I only film short videos with the short cut. Yeah, sexy, right?
そして、ステージがなんか凄かっこいい！かっこ良すぎる！
And the stage looks super cool! Way too cool!
今回はこんな感じなんですね！今日はなんか色々楽しみなことがいっぱいありそうだけど...
So this time it's like this! There seem to be lots of fun things to look forward to today, but...
えー！一体何で今日このステージなんだろうなぁ？んー、なんと後でね...
Woah! Why on earth is it this stage today? Hmm, well, later on...
ロボ子がいるらしいんですけれど...
There seems to be a Robosa around...
コメントにいないロボ子がいるらしくてですね
Apparently there's a Robosa who isn't in the comments...
気になった子を探してみてくださいね
Try looking for the one you're curious about.
いるかなー？
I wonder if they're here?
あれ？ロボ子いるかなー？
Huh? Is there a Robosa here?
あれー？いるかなー？
Huh? Are they here?
きっと目が...見つけてるやつ多い
I bet a lot of you have already spotted them!
あ、正解！正解！ここにいます！
Ah, correct! Correct! Here they are!
特等席！お前は一体誰なんだー！
A front-row seat! Who on earth are you?!
ずっと僕のことリハ中も見守っててくれてるマスコットロボ子可愛ちーね
The mascot Robosa watching over me during rehearsal is so cute!
はい！というわけで、今日は誕生日のために
Alright! So today, for my birthday...
いっぱい、いっぱい、みんな、そして僕が楽しめる歌をたくさんねご用意いたしましたので
I've prepared lots and lots of songs that everyone and I can enjoy!
いっぱいレッスンもしたので楽しんでいってください！
I practiced a lot too, so please enjoy!
はい！この後は...
Alright! After this...
そろそろ一人でも歌うと思うんだけど...
I think I'll be singing solo soon, but...
ゲストも呼んでって歌っちゃおうかなーと思います！
I'm also planning to invite guests to sing together!
最初は誰だろうなー？最初は誰だろうなー？
Who will be first? Who will be first?
なんか、すごいキスいっぱいしたい気分になってきた
Somehow, I'm feeling like giving lots of kisses...
なんでだろう？なんでだろ？
Why is that? Why, I wonder?
ちゅっちゅっちゅっ、ちゅー！
Mwah mwah mwah, mwah!
モエチャッカファイア
[Title: Moe Cha-ka Fire]
よくぞお越しくださった ご主人様
Welcome, Master, thank you for coming
お隣座って せーのっ
Sit right beside me, ready...
萌え 萌え 萌え 萌え
Moe moe moe moe
こんなの誰が喜ぶのさ
Who is going to be happy with this?
ねぇ教えて 笑顔でアップップ
Hey, tell me, with a smile, face off!
愛想を振って ご苦労様
Good job acting so friendly
私とあなたで せーのっ
You and me together, ready...
だんだん だんだん
Dandan dandan
こうやって誰か喜ぶのさ
This is how someone gets happy
ねぇ教えて 笑顔でアップップ
Hey, tell me, with a smile, face off!
ひらりひらり 女の子
Fluttering, fluttering, a girl
ふわりふわり 言葉の嘘
Softly, softly, lies of words
それってつまり治まらない
Which means, uncontainable
感情的リアル 笑顔でアップップ
Emotional reality, with a smile, face off!
人は見かけによらぬもの
People aren't what they look like
嘘を嘘と見抜けばいい
You just have to spot a lie as a lie
じっと鷹の空目その中は
Looking closely, inside those hawk-eyes
やっぱり腹黒 鮫肌 あんた
As expected, black-hearted, rough skin, you
間違ったご指名をいただきます
I'll accept your mistaken request
私とあなたで せーのっ
You and me together, ready...
だんだん だんだん
Dandan dandan
これはこれで心様
This is fine in its own way, dear heart
遊びましょう 笑顔でアップップ
Let me play, with a smile, face off!
ひらりひらり ここはどこ
Fluttering, fluttering, where is this?
ふわりふわり そこへ逃避行
Softly, softly, escaping to over there
それってつまり治まらない
Which means, uncontainable
感情的リアル 笑顔でアップップ
Emotional reality, with a smile, face off!
占い出す 秘密の鐘
Foretelling, secret bell
終わることのない この世界
This world that never ends
哀しい子供は
A sad child is...
眠らせて
Put to sleep
あままごと 遊びましょう
Playing house, let's play
笑顔でアップップ
With a smile, face off!
ひらりひらり 女の子
Fluttering, fluttering, a girl
ふわりふわり 言葉の嘘
Softly, softly, lies of words
それってつまり治まらない
Which means, uncontainable
感情的リアル 笑顔でアップップ
Emotional reality, with a smile, face off!
遊びましょう 笑顔でアップップ
Let's play, with a smile, face off!
アップップ
Up-pu-ppu
あれが世界なんて
Calling that the world...
G4L
[Title: G4L]
誰の誰の果て
Whose, whose end is it?
答えも欲しいんだ もうイイでこれだけ？
I want answers too, is this all that's good enough?
悩んだって しょうがないじゃんね
Worrying won't change a thing, right?
あれは夢だったって 思えば思い通りだって
Thinking "that was just a dream" makes it go as planned
全然ゼロ問題だけど 助けてよ FOLLOW ME
Zero problem at all, but save me, follow me
TAKE OUT OUTTA HERE 理由なんか無くたって
Take out outta here, even without any reason
MAKE IT LOUD, MAKE IT LOUD LACKY LACKY LACKY
有り得よう 割り切れたら 最高
If it could happen, if I could compromise, it'd be the best
だけどなのにどうか
But even so, somehow...
ああ もう嫌だ
Ah, I hate this already.
なんちゅー新世界か
What kind of new world is this?
あんた以外は
Anyone other than you...
あんた以外はいらない ない ない
I don't need anyone besides you, no, no!
払えよバリア
Tear down the barrier!
あるはずのない何か
Something that shouldn't exist...
あったならばハッピー ジャンピング (Yeah)
If it's there, happy jumping, yeah!
あんたのその手と アジトの底 繋いだ手 離さないわ
Your hand and mine, deep in the hideout, I won't let go of our joined hands.
あんたのその手が アジトの底 掴んだ 最終のお見知りおきを My love
Deep in the hideout, your hand grabbed it—remember this final moment, my love.
へえ、これで終わりなんて
Huh, to think it ends like this...
あがってないままなんて
Still not feeling hyped up at all...
どうにかなっちゃえて 願って 願ってね
Praying and wishing for something to happen, right?
悪癖したりしちゃうんだ
I end up falling into bad habits.
何も我慢できん ペンペン
I can't hold back anything at all!
痛いと言えばエブリデイ
Complaining about pain every single day.
マウント取れるけどな ブルベ夏なんで関係ない
I could flex on you, but I'm a cool-toned summer type, so whatever.
カレーよりも猫
Cats over curry.
切ないのも結構
Heartbreak is fine too.
あたしはあたしだ 見といてよ レディ
I am who I am, watch me, lady!
もう今日で終わらせたいなって
Wishing I could just end it all today...
リスタート出来たらって
Wishing I could hit restart...
でも無理よね
But that's impossible, right?
無理よ 割り切れたらさ 無理よ
Impossible, if only I could rationalize it... impossible.
だけどなのにどうか
But even so, somehow...
ああ もう嫌だ
Ah, I hate this already.
なんちゅー新世界か
What kind of new world is this?
あんた以外は
Anyone other than you...
あんた以外はいらない ない ない
I don't need anyone besides you, no, no!
払えよバリア
Tear down the barrier!
あるはずのない何か
Something that shouldn't exist...
あったならばハッピー ジャンピング (Yeah)
If it's there, happy jumping, yeah!
あんたのその手と アジトの底 繋いだ手 離さないわ
Your hand and mine, deep in the hideout, I won't let go of our joined hands.
あんたのその手が アジトの底 掴んだ 最終のお見知りおきを My love
Deep in the hideout, your hand grabbed it—remember this final moment, my love.
なーなー もうあかん
Nah nah, no way anymore.
お見知りおきを My love
Remember this moment, my love.
半端なら K.O.
Half-baked efforts get a K.O.!
ふわふわしたいなら どうぞ
If you wanna float around, go right ahead.
開演準備しちゃおうか
Shall we get ready for the curtain call?
泣いても笑っても愛してね
Whether crying or laughing, love me anyway.
ほらせーの
Here we go, ready, set...
手を叩かせろ
Make them clap their hands!
なんだかんだつまらない事もあるでしょう
One way or another, boring things happen, right?
ノリノリになっちゃって 張り合ってみよう
Let's get into the groove and compete!
世の中って ドローにバットハットだろうが
Whether this world is a draw or a bad hat,
おぼれて落ちて
drown and fall down!
えー
Yeah!
いっそ無策でいっそ乗っちゃって
Better to have no plan and just ride with it,
踊るまでもっと頑張って
push harder until we dance!
繋がろう ひとりよりふたり
Let's connect, two is better than one!
増えたら安心 心配ないや
More people mean relief, no need to worry!
オーライ まかせて DON'T MIND
All right, leave it to me, don't mind!
ノリノリでみんなで乗っかっちゃえば
If everyone gets hyped and jumps on board,
案外サクッといけそう
it might be surprisingly easy!
半端なら K.O.
Half-baked efforts get a K.O.!
ふわふわしたいなら どうぞ
If you wanna float around, go right ahead.
開演準備しちゃおうか
Shall we get ready for the curtain call?
泣いても笑っても愛してね
Whether crying or laughing, love me anyway.
ほらせーの
Here we go, ready, set...
手を叩かせろ
Make them clap their hands!
今夜はアセバリ
Tonight is all about dripping sweat!
踊りだせ 踊りだせ ほらドサクサに紛れ
Start dancing, start dancing, amidst all the confusion!
痛みまで 推し進め ここらで バイバイ ドクター
Push through even the pain, bye-bye Doctor right around here!
どんなレトロ感だって 即興の結晶版で
No matter how retro it feels, in this improvised perfection,
最高で突っ込んじゃうでしょ
we'll dive right in at our absolute best, right?
アッパーなテンションで 参っちゃっての最高
Overwhelmed by high-voltage hype, it's the ultimate thrill!
ドバっと吹き出すのは 本音の独り言
Gushing out suddenly are my genuine monologues!
別に興味ない (ない)
Not really interested (no way).
そこに関係ない (ない)
Has nothing to do with it (no way).
カサコソ絶好調
Rustling along in top condition!
アイツを奏でて Clap clap clap yeah
Play that beat, clap clap clap yeah!
ほら集まって
Hey, gather around!
夜更かしだ
We're staying up late!
最低な
The absolute worst...
半端なら K.O.
If you're half-assed, K.O.
踊らせよ 踊らせよ 孤独の隙間 舞い降り
Let them dance, let them dance, fluttering into the gaps of solitude.
痛みまで おしゃれ 今宵もアセンブリーだ
Even pain is stylish, tonight is another assembly.
お待ちのお越しを じっと...
Patiently waiting for your arrival...
次までお元気で ここらでバイバイライオナー
Stay well until next time, bye-bye lioner around here.
いや うなだれてるその兄ちゃん
Hey, you slumped-over buddy,
なんか辛いことあったんか
did something tough happen?
俺で良けりゃ話してくんない
If I'll do, why not talk to me?
力になるぜ
I'll lend you a hand.
一体どんなことがあった？
Just what on earth happened?
それ言ってみな兄弟
Go on and tell me, brother.
これをやるから元気出しな
Take this and cheer up,
金ならまた今度でいいさ
as for the money, next time is fine.
シャンティ シャンティ シャンティ シャンティ シャンティ
Shanti Shanti Shanti Shanti Shanti
確信犯的 ハッピー ハッピー ハッピー キャンディ
Premeditated happy, happy, happy candy,
マニー マニー マニー
money, money, money.
眠らない夜の街のダンス そのすべてが縄張り
The dance in this sleepless night town, all of it is my turf.
どうにもならないお立ち台の上で 踊り明かしていりゃいい
On this helpless podium, just dance the night away.
今夜もお気になったかい
Did you take a liking tonight as well?
お気に召したかい
Did it suit your fancy?
代金はこちらくらい で え？え？
The price is about this much... Huh? Huh?
払えないのかい？
Can't pay?
ならばしょうがない
Well then, it can't be helped.
君にピッタリの仕事があるから
I've got a job that's perfect for you, so...
こっちについて来な
follow me over here.
Follow me over here.
こっちについて来な
嫌がられて坂が剥がれた女
A woman shunned, her facade peeling away,
しゃがれた看板掲げたオーナー
an owner holding up a weathered sign.
高々マイクで逸れた用事じゃ
If it's just business derailed over a simple mic,
端からあいつの思惑通りだ
it's been playing into their hands from the start.
奇々怪々な目散歩中
Bizarre eyes taking a stroll,
散るって分かって納得
understanding and accepting that it will scatter.
超人的動作で咲かせた花で
With flowers bloomed through superhuman feats,
盲心の真ん中へ
right into the heart of blind devotion.
黙れ 坐れ 黙れ や
Shut up, sit down, shut up, yeah.
殴れ 殴れ 殴れ や
Strike, strike, strike, yeah.
縛れ 縛れ 縛れ や
Bind, bind, bind, yeah.
バラせ バラせ バラせ や
Expose, expose, expose, yeah.
今夜のお味はどうだい
How does tonight taste?
お気に召したかい
Did it suit your fancy?
代金はこちらくらい
The price is about this much.
生きていれば客
If you're alive, a customer;
死んでいれば食材
if you're dead, ingredients.
そつなくこなして転がすビジネス
Handling business smoothly and rolling right along,
どっちを向いてんだ
which way are you looking?
Which way are you looking?
どっちを向いてんだ
いや うなだれてるその嬢ちゃん
Hey, you slumped-over missy,
俺で良けりゃ話してくんない
if I'll do, why not talk to me?
はーい！というわけで
Hi! And so...
かっこいいでしょ？
Cool, right?
はい！こちらがロボ子の新衣装となります！
Yes! This is Roboco's new outfit!
見て、下から！超かっこいいの！
Look from below! It's super cool!
どうよ？え、サングラス似合いすぎでは？
How is it? Eh, don't the sunglasses suit me way too well?
やばい、みんなが恋しちゃう！
Oh no, everyone's gonna fall in love!
俺に惚れると火傷するぜ？
If you fall for me, you'll get burned!
いや、イベくさすぎる！
Wait, that's way too cheesy!
笑わないで！笑うのやめてね！
Don't laugh! Stop laughing, okay?
はい！というわけで...
Alright! So anyway...
見て、これ！かっこいいでしょー！
Look at this! Cool, right?
なんかさ、指についてんだけど、まだよく見えないね？
Like, there's something on my fingers, but you can't really see it yet, right?
まだ、まだよく見えないね！
Still, can't really see it well yet!
え、『踊』のときにカラーライズ衣装からチェンジしたんだけど...
Eh, during "Odo" I changed from the Colorize outfit, but...
チェンジした瞬間、ちゃんとみんなわかった？
The moment I changed, did everyone notice clearly?
あ、湧いてくれました？
Ah, did it pop up for you?
一瞬だったでしょう？
It happened in a flash, right?
嬉しい！
I'm so happy!
可愛い！かっこいい！
Cute! Cool!
ね、これなんか両方あるよね、かっこいいし可愛いよね
Right? This has both—cool and cute!
プリティーでクールなの、これ
It's pretty and cool.
いっぱい見て、いっぱい見て。足からちょっと見ていく？
Take a good look! Shall we check it out starting from the feet?
うわ、見... えぇ？
Woah, look... huh?
やばい！カッコ良すぎるんだが！
Insane! This is way too cool!
見て、これロボット特有のさ、この...
Look, this is robot-exclusive, this...
これ人間だったら多分めっちゃ歩きづらいんじゃない？
If a human wore this, it'd probably be super hard to walk in, right?
みんな多分歩けないよね、この靴
Everyone probably couldn't walk in these shoes.
僕歩けるんだけどさ
I can walk in them, though.
うん、この靴で多分僕走ったら多分めっちゃ
Yeah, and if I ran in these shoes, I'd probably...
倍転ぶと思うから歩きます
fall twice as hard, so I'll just walk.
どう、どう、どう？
How is it, how is it?
はい、そして上からね
Alright, moving up...
かっこよく決まって、ベルトあればあるだけ良いですから！
Looking sleek and cool—the more belts there are, the better!
いっぱい付けてもらいました！
They put so many on for me!
今回マジで装飾品もね、かっこいい！ギラギラ！
This time, seriously, even the accessories are cool! So flashy!
金色のネックレス。これダイヤとか雷が付いてるのかな？
A gold necklace. Does this have diamonds and lightning bolts on it?
あと、なんか姿がちょっとおかしくなってるけど
Also, like, my form is getting a bit glitchy, but...
僕の新衣装に合わせてロボ子のアライヤリングに似たり、新しい丸メガネは
Matching my new outfit, these ear rings look like Roboco's logo, and the new round glasses are...
ちょっとクールで装飾品もいっぱい付いてるし
a bit cool with lots of accessories attached...
何よりこのデッカイお団子かわちいでしょう！
Above all, these huge hair buns are super cute, right?!
モフモフモフモフ... 僕、毛量多いの大好き！
Fluffy fluffy fluffy... I love high-volume hair!
ね！このモフモフも可愛いよね
Right! This fluff is cute too, isn't it?
これ脱げるのかって？ えー、だって指だってまだちゃんと見れてないもんね
Can I take this off, you ask? Eh~ but we haven't even properly looked at my fingers yet!
脱げちゃうのかな、後で
Will I be able to take it off later?
後でお楽しみにしててください！
Please look forward to it later!
はい！というわけで、え、でも...
Alright! So anyway... wait, but...
ライブ以来だよ、カラーライズ衣装着たの！
It's been since the live concert that I wore a color-rized outfit!
かっこ良かったでしょう？ギャル！
It was so cool, right? Gal!
ね！めちゃくちゃ映えてたよね、うん
Right?! It looked so amazing, yeah!
『萌えジャッカファイア』もね！
'Moe Jacka Fire' too!
もう早くね、エリザベスが3Dモデル出るの僕待ってるから！ベス！
I'm waiting so eagerly for Elizabeth's 3D model to come out! Beth!
ね！でも一緒に歌えてすごい楽しかった！ありがとうね、みんな！
Right! But singing together was so much fun! Thank you everyone!
はい、そして大凶とシャンティとイタズラも歌いましたけれども...
Yes, and we also sang Daikyou, Shanti, and Itazura, but...
爆上げ！かっこ良すぎロボ子さん！
Super hyped! Roboco-san is way too cool!
言っておきますからね！ロボ子の低音が好きすぎる民たち
I'll say it right now to all of you who love Roboco's low voice so much:
いつもありがとう。すごく嬉しい。僕も気持ち良く歌えました！
Thank you as always. I'm super happy. I had a blast singing too!
あ、ところでステージがなんか進化してドラゴン君が生まれてたの気付きました？
Ah, by the way, did you notice the stage evolved and Mr. Dragon was born?
こいつどこから来たんやね、お前ね！ロボ子食われちゃいそうだよね！
Where on earth did you come from?! It looks like Roboco's gonna get eaten!
一回ロボ子をね、ドラゴンの口の中に入れてみようかね、ちょっと悩んだ
I actually thought about putting Roboco inside the dragon's mouth once,
でも入れなかった、僕偉い！
but I didn't! Good job me!
うわ、あいつの上に乗ってみたすぎるだろ、うん...
Woah, I wanna ride on top of him so bad...
というわけでですね、もう次の歌も歌いたいんですけれど...
So, anyway, I want to sing the next song already, but...
せっかくね、この衣装なので、なんかゲストの中にめっちゃシナジーある奴がいるらしいんですよ
since I'm wearing this outfit, apparently there's a guest with insane synergy!
歌っちゃおうかなー！ね、ドラゴン君
Should I sing with them?! Right, Mr. Dragon?
歌いたいよねー！ねー！
You wanna sing too, right?!
あー、歌いたい！
Ah~ I wanna sing!
って言ってる気がするんで
I feel like he's saying that.
じゃあ早速呼んでいきましょう！
Alright, let's call them over right away!
み、み、みどりー！
Mi, Mi, Midori~!
ロボ子久々！お誕生日おめでとう！
Roboco, long time no see! Happy birthday!
ユーちゃん、ありがとう！ね、見て見て、衣装！
Yuu-chan, thank you! Hey, look look, my outfit!
めっちゃ可愛い！めっちゃ格好良い！
Super cute! Super cool!
一緒に『いーあるふぁんくらぶ』歌おう！
Let's sing "1, 2 Fanclub" together!
いいよー！
Sure!
神戸 中央区 モトマチ (駅前)
Kobe, Chuuou-ku, Motomachi (in front of the station)
今日から ドキドキ ニハオハンザー 講座
Starting today, the thrilling "Nihao" Chinese class
大人 中高生 おばちゃんに
To adults, middle/high school students, and middle-aged ladies
「こんにちは」
"Hello"
ダメダメ ここでは あなたも
No, no! Here, you too must say...
「ニーハオ」
"Nihao"
マジで テキスト 三ページ
Seriously, page 3 of the textbook
ここは神戸 とにかく学習塾に通うぞ
Here is Kobe, anyway I'll attend cram school.
1万3千の授業料は
The 13,000 yen tuition fee...
安くない
...is not cheap!
黄華大兄 ご機嫌いかが
Hello, Big Brother Huang Hua, how are you?
お母さん お馬さん
Mother, horse.
ここはどこ 君は誰
Where is this? Who are you?
大好きなワン・リーホンに
To Wang Leehom, whom I love so much,
大好きだって言うため
just to say "I love you,"
ハイハイ チャイナ ちょちょ 夢心地
Hi-hi China, a sweet dreamlike mood,
いーある ふぁんくらぶ
Yi-er Fanclub.
だんだん 君と同じ言葉が
Gradually, the same words as you...
使えるね
...I can speak them now.
ウォーアイニー 言えるかな
Can I say "Wo ai ni"?
ねぇ見て 竜ちゃん
Hey look, Ryu-chan!
竜
Dragon!
竜ちゃん
Ryu-chan!
竜
Dragon!
そこで知り合った女子高生
A high school girl I met there,
曰く 台湾で流行ってるのは周杰倫
she says Jay Chou is popular in Taiwan.
それは行かなきゃダメだ
Then I gotta go!
ところでJK ルー・シーチェっと言ってるけど海外だよ
By the way, JK, you say Lu Xi Che, but that's overseas!
マジで エンジンかかってきた
Seriously, I'm getting revved up.
ここはとにかく便乗して頑張るか
Anyway, let's jump on the bandwagon and do our best!
6万8千の旅費も
The 68,000 yen travel expense...
それでは背に腹は代えられない バイト探さなきゃ
Desperate times call for desperate measures, gotta find a part-time job.
すみません お嬢さん
Excuse me, young lady,
これ一つ いくらでしょう
how much is just one of these?
天国のレスリー・チャンに
To Leslie Cheung in heaven,
おやすみなさいって言うため
to say "good night,"
ハイハイ チャイナ ちょちょ 夢心地
Hi-hi China, a sweet dreamlike mood,
いーある ふぁんくらぶ
Yi-er Fanclub.
だんだん 君の伝えたい気持ちが
Gradually, the feelings you want to convey...
分かってく
...I start to understand.
憧れて 夢中になって
Longing, becoming obsessed,
一ヶ月 二ヶ月
one month, two months,
半年過ぎた
half a year has passed.
リア友は少し減ったけど
My real-life friends decreased a bit, but
それも仕方ないや
that can't be helped either.
ハイハイ チャイナ ちょちょ 夢心地
Hi-hi China, a sweet dreamlike mood,
いーある ふぁんくらぶ
Yi-er Fanclub.
だんだん 君と同じ言葉が
Gradually, the same words as you...
使えるね
...I can speak them now.
ハイハイ チャイナ ちょちょ 夢心地
Hi-hi China, a sweet dreamlike mood,
いーある ふぁんくらぶ
Yi-er Fanclub.
だんだん 君の伝えたい気持ちが
Gradually, the feelings you want to convey...
分かってく
...I start to understand.
ウォーアイニー 言わせてよ
Let me say "Wo ai ni."
いーある ふぁんくらぶ
Yi-er Fanclub.
ウォーアイニー 言えるかな
Can I say "Wo ai ni"?
大丈夫？ みんな
Are you okay, everyone?
うわー！ びっくりした！ ありがとう！
Whoa! That scared me! Thank you!
連打やめてね
Stop spamming the buttons, haha.
大丈夫？ みんな
Are you okay, everyone?
ありがとう、ありがとう、ありがとう！
Thank you, thank you, thank you!
素敵
Lovely.
え？ 素敵じゃない？ あなた
Eh? Aren't you lovely?
どこが素敵？
Where am I lovely?
もちろん…
Of course...
太もも
Thighs.
ねぇー 全然隠せてないの
Hey! You're not hiding them at all!
もちろん
Of course.
太ももフェチなの？ 太もも…
Are you a thigh fetishist? Thighs...
好き
I like them.
どこら辺？ 太ももの…
Whereabouts? On the thigh...
え、エッチだから
Eh, because it's sexy.
ねぇー！
Hey!
大好きそういうの
I love stuff like that.
ちょっと露出してるの ちょっとだけ
Slightly exposed. Just a little bit.
で、素敵じゃないですか
And isn't that lovely?
いいよねー
It's nice, right~
でも、あなたもね
But you too,
ここ好き！ この…
I like this! This...
ここ！
Here!
ここフェチ！ たまんねー！
Thigh-gap fetish! Unresistable!
たまんねー？
Unresistable?
最高だ！
It's the best!
人のこと言えない
Look who's talking.
お互いそういう絡みしかできない やばい
We can only banter with each other like this, oh boy.
長年の適当な絡みになっちゃってよぉ
It's turned into our usual casual banter after all these years.
適当な緑仙でーす
It's casual Ryushen~
緑仙が来てくれましたー！
Ryushen came here to join us!
バッチリでしょ、今回
We're totally in sync this time, right?
もう呼びたくて呼びたくて仕方はなかった
I wanted to invite you so, so badly!
嬉しい
I'm happy.
歌えたのがね、まず嬉しいよ
Being able to sing together, first of all, makes me happy.
あ、そうだよね！確かに
Ah, that's true! Indeed.
歌ったことないね
We've never sung together.
そうなんですよ！歌ったことなかったから
That's right! We've never sung together before.
喋りながらポーズしておこうと思って
I thought I'd pose while talking.
待って
Wait.
待って！みんな落ち着け！
Wait! Everyone, calm down!
落ち着いて
Calm down.
写真は撮っていい勝手に
Feel free to take photos as you like.
いい感じで撮っていい
You can take good screenshots.
勝手にスクショ撮って、タグを付け投稿してほしい
Take screenshots freely, tag them, and post them!
ハッシュタグは何ですか？
What is the hashtag?
ハッシュタグは…
The hashtag is...
そんなことはここを見ればわかるだろ！
If you look right here, you'd know that!
端折らないでよ
Don't cut corners!
えぇ～ 長年だと手抜くんですか？
Eh~ You cut corners just because we've known each other for years?
そんなことないです！
No way!
何ですか途中の…
What was that midway...
上、指さして
...pointing up!
だってあなたの名前って、緑仙じゃないですか
Because your name is Ryushen, right?
緑仙ですよ
I am Ryushen.
竜、あ、竜！あ、竜！ほらほら竜、竜、竜！
Ryu, ah, Ryu! Ah, Ryu! Look look, Ryu, Ryu, Ryu!
イテーってなっちゃった。
It hit me and hurt...
だっ、だってあそこ僕に任されたんだ、多分！
Because, because I think I was put in charge of that!
しかもさ、僕のことさ、あの、「竜ちゃん」って呼んでるよね？今日。
Plus, you've been calling me "Ryu-chan" today, right?
うん、「竜ちゃん」！今日だけ。
Yeah, "Ryu-chan"! Only today.
でも、普段は「緑」とか言うんですよ。
But usually, you call me "Midori" and stuff.
今日だけ！「竜ちゃん」とか言って！
Only today! Saying things like "Ryu-chan"!
竜ちゃん！
Ryu-chan!
いや、なんか幼馴染面で近寄ってきたのと思って。すごいドキドキしてます。
I was like, "Are you approaching me acting like a childhood friend?"... I'm so nervous.
え、本当？可愛くぶっちゃった！
Really? I was playing cute!
可愛い。そのポーズ可愛い、これ。え、可愛いでしょ？
Cute. That pose is cute. - Isn't it cute?
可愛いですよ。
It's cute.
可愛い。 / 竜ちゃん、見て見て！
Cute. - Ryu-chan, look, look!
えー、可愛い。 / 切っちゃった！
Aw, cute. - I cut them!
ね、みんな僕の分も褒めてあげてください。僕はあんまり褒めないので。
Everyone, please compliment her for me too. I don't compliment much.
えっ、褒めろよ！ / いや可愛い、本当に可愛い。
Eh? Compliment me! - No, it's cute, really cute.
ほら竜ちゃんもあざといポーズしろ！ / え、一緒にやろう。
Come on, Ryu-chan, do a cute calculated pose too! - Eh, let's do it together.
しよう！ / え、可愛い！
Let's! - Aw, cute!
キュルン！ / キュルン。かっこいい、可愛い、最高やないの。
Kyurun! - Kyurun. Cool, cute, isn't it the best?
いいんじゃないですか。
Isn't it good?
なんかポーズしようよ。 / 希望あれば。
Let's do a pose. - If you have any requests.
パンチ！ / パンチ？でもね、クソリプパンチしたもんね、我々一緒に。
Punch! - Punch? But we did the crap reply punch together, didn't we?
超強パンチ！ / 超強パンチ？
Super strong punch! - Super strong punch?
かかってこいや！ / 最高！強そう！
Come at us! - Awesome! We look strong!
本当に強そうになっちゃった。
We really ended up looking strong.
撃退したいリプライとかあったらね、これ使ってもらって。 / ね、使ってください！
If there's any reply you want to fend off, feel free to use this. - Yeah, please use it!
かかってこい！ / 僕たちが倒します。
Come at us! - We will defeat them.
かかってこい、かかってこい！ / クソリプ…クソリプ、全て倒します。
Come at us, come at us! - Crap replies... Crap replies, we'll defeat them all.
え、見て！竜ちゃん好きそう！
Look! Ryu-chan, you look like you'd like this!
可愛い、マジで可愛い、本当に。
Cute, seriously cute, really.
好きそう、素敵！ / いいですね。ちょっとポーズはさておき、素敵よ。
Looks like you'd like it, awesome! - Nice. Setting the pose aside, it's wonderful.
やったー！ポーズも褒めて！
Yay! Compliment the pose too!
適当なポーズも褒めて！
Compliment the random pose too!
めちゃくちゃいい感じでしょう！強そう！
It looks so good, right? Strong!
靴可愛い！ / え、もう止まんないよ、褒め出したら。
The shoes are cute! - Eh, once I start complimenting, I won't stop.
やばいやばい、嬉しい！ / 今日は特にね。
Oh no oh no, I'm so happy! - Especially today.
今日呼んで良かった！ / 呼んでくれてありがとう。
I'm so glad I invited you today! - Thank you for inviting me.
ありがた、ありがた！
Thank you, thank you!
今日はね、まだ…
Today, we still have...
いや、締めの下手さ元々… / 頑張ってね！
Wait, your wrap-up is bad as always... - Good luck!
頑張ってねー！ / ねー、テイタサーン！
Good luck~! - Right, Teita-san~!
あいつマジで本当に雑なんだよー！
They are seriously so abrupt!
はい、というわけで緑でした！竜ちゃんでも何でも呼んであげてください！
Alright, so that was Midori! Please call them Ryu-chan or whatever you like!
じゃあロボ子は次頑張りますので！
Well then, Roboco will do her best next!
I wanna do it do it yeah
チャイナアドバイス
China Advice
泡と消えそうなチャイナ
China fading like bubbles
I wanna do it do it yeah
泡もはじけるチャイナ
China with bursting bubbles
ロボ子さんお誕生日おめでとう！ / ありがとう！
Happy birthday, Roboco-san! - Thank you!
春茶、バーチャルの世界へようこそー！ / 下も黒になっちゃった、僕の服。
Harutya, welcome to the virtual world~! - The bottom of my clothes turned black too.
マイク！
Microphone!
いってきます！
Here I go!
我爱你 君に 我爱你 我爱你 我爱你 あなたに
Wo ai ni, to you, wo ai ni, wo ai ni, wo ai ni, to you
えーっと 簡単に 落ちる 我爱你 我爱你 我爱你
Um, easily falling, wo ai ni, wo ai ni, wo ai ni
I wanna do it do it yeah
泡と消えそうなチャイナ
China fading like bubbles
I wanna do it do it yeah
泡もはじけるチャイナ
China with bursting bubbles
天頂のモモに 君に 我爱你 我爱你 我爱你 そこに
Peach at the zenith, to you, wo ai ni, wo ai ni, wo ai ni, right there
中途の後悔に 終わる 我爱你 我爱你 我爱你
Ending in half-hearted regret, wo ai ni, wo ai ni, wo ai ni
そんなやつ やめチャイナ チャイナ チャイナ チャイナ チャイナ チャイナアドバイス
Just dump a guy like that, China China China China, China advice
もうわたしの虜にしれチャイナ チャイナ チャイナ チャイナ チャイナアドバイス
Make him fall for me, China China China, China advice
I wanna do it do it yeah
泡と消えそうなチャイナ
China fading like bubbles
I wanna do it do it yeah
泡もはじけるチャイナ
China with bursting bubbles
表情の限界に 潜む 我爱你 我爱你 我爱你 そう曖昧に
Lurking at the limit of expressions, wo ai ni, wo ai ni, wo ai ni, so ambiguously
大脳の限界に 挑む 我爱你 我爱你 我爱你
Challenging the limits of the brain, wo ai ni, wo ai ni, wo ai ni
そろそろ やめチャイナ チャイナ チャイナ チャイナ チャイナ チャイナアドバイス
It's about time to quit, China China China China, China advice
いい加減にお友達の チャイナ チャイナ チャイナ チャイナ チャイナアドバイス
Enough with being just friends, China China China China, China advice
I wanna do it do it yeah
泡と消えそうなチャイナ
China fading like bubbles
I wanna do it do it yeah
泡もはじけるチャイナ
China with bursting bubbles
そんなやつ やめチャイナ チャイナ チャイナ チャイナ チャイナ チャイナ
Just dump a guy like that, China China China China China China
アドバイス
Advice,
もう私の虜にし
I'll make you fall for me completely.
チャイナ チャイナ チャイナ チャイナ アドバイス
China, China, China, China Advice!
サーティワン 手紙に書いて
Write '31' in a letter,
チャイナ チャイナ チャイナ チャイナ アドバイス
China, China, China, China Advice!
あぁ 私も虜にし
Ah, make me fall for you too,
チャイナ チャイナ 財産 チャイナ アドバイス
China, China, fortune, China Advice!
はるちゃん！
Haru-chan!
嬉しい！ 一緒に歌えて！
I'm so happy we got to sing together!
楽しかった！
It was so much fun!
楽しかった！ ありがとう！
It was fun! Thank you!
ありがとう！ こちらこそ！
Thank you too!
はるちゃん、そこから出ないの？ 今日
Haru-chan, aren't you coming out from there today?
そう
Yeah.
ここがうち...
This is my home...
すごいよね、これね
This is pretty amazing, isn't it?
え、すごいよね！
Yeah, it really is!
というわけで、今日ははるちゃんがゲストに来てくれました！
So today, Haru-chan came as our guest!
こんにちは！
Hello!
はるちゃです
I'm Harucha.
はるちゃがさ、すごいさ、多分みんなも「そこ接点あるの？」って
Having Harucha here... Everyone's probably thinking, "Wait, do they even know each other?"
多分めっちゃ思われると思うんだよね
I bet a lot of people are wondering that.
確かに
True.
1回だけね、ポストとかでね
Just once on a post...
そう、お土産をね、あげたの！
Yeah, I gave her a souvenir!
そう、もらった
Yeah, I got it.
そう、で、実ははるちゃんからも僕はお土産をもらってる
Right, and actually, I got a souvenir from Haru-chan too.
確かにあげたわ
True, I did give you one.
そう！でもそれはポストしてない
Yeah! But I didn't post about that one!
そう、なんだかんだね、結構遊んでたりもしましたからね
Yeah, we've actually hung out quite a bit behind the scenes.
今回はお呼びしました！ どうでしたか？
So I invited her today! How was it?
どうでしたか？
How was it?
私に聞いてるの？
Are you asking me?
みんなに聞いてる
I'm asking everyone.
え、でもどうだった？ 一緒に歌って
Well, how was it for you, singing together?
超楽しかった
It was super fun.
え、嬉しい！ 僕も楽しかった！
Aw, I'm happy to hear that! I had fun too!
ね、初めて歌ってさ
Right, singing together for the first time...
歌ったよね？
We sang, right?
こういう場所でね！
In a place like this!
だってさ、声色が結構近いからさ、絶対これ似合うやと思って
Because our voice tones are pretty close, I knew this song would suit us so well,
今回は「チャイナアドバイス」選びました！
so I chose "China Advice" for us!
ロボ子が決めたの？
Roboko chose it?
うん！
Yep!
神選曲でしょ？
It's a god-tier song pick, right?
すごい、神選曲。さすが
Amazing, god-tier pick. As expected.
はるちゃんがさ、珍しいんだよ。僕のことロボ子って呼ぶの
Haru-chan calling me Roboko is pretty rare, you know.
あ、そうなの？
Oh, really?
あんまりいないの、マジで
Hardly anyone does, seriously.
そう、聞いてびっくりした
Yeah, I was surprised when I heard that.
そう、もうナチュラルにずっと「ロボ子」なの
Yeah, she naturally just calls me "Roboko" all the time.
逆に何？ 何が多いの？
What do people usually call you then?
ええ？「ロボちゃん」とか、やっぱ「先輩」とか？
Huh? Like "Robo-chan", or "Senpai"?
あーね、それはちょっとよく分かんない
Ah, right. I don't really get that.
先輩なの？ ロボ子
Are you a senpai, Roboko?
そう、先輩なんだよ、一応
Yeah, I am your senpai, technically.
え、ねぇねぇ、これホントやりたかったけど忘れてた
Hey, hey, I really wanted to do this earlier, but I forgot!
ハート作れます
We can make a heart.
あ、いけそうじゃない？
Oh, looks like we can!
あ！ みんな写真撮って！
Ah! Everyone, take a screenshot!
でもいい感じやん
It looks pretty good though!
え、可愛い！ これ新しい衣装なんですけれど
Aw, cute! By the way, this is my new outfit.
超可愛いと思います
I think it's super cute.
え、はるちゃん的におすすめのポーズとかあったら取っちゃうんだけど...
If you have any recommended poses, Haru-chan, I'll do them!
ちょっとあれやってよ、上目遣い
Do that upturned glance pose.
上目遣い？
Upturned glance?
可愛い、可愛い
Cute, cute!
はるちゃん...
Haru-chan...
いっぱい遊んでね
Play with me lots, okay?
いっぱい遊ぼう！
Let's play lots!
でも手はゴツいんだね
Though your hands look pretty rugged.
ね、そうなの。めちゃめちゃかっこいい。見て！
Right? They're super cool. Look!
え、でも好きでしょ？ こういうの
You like stuff like this, right?
ゴッツい！ かっこいい！ これめっちゃ高い！
Rugged! Cool! These were super expensive!
高いんだ
They're expensive?
めっちゃ高い！ たぶんパパが作ってくれた！
Super expensive! My papa made them for me!
パパもすごいな
Your papa is amazing too.
お団子もさ、超可愛くない？
Aren't these hair buns super cute too?
え、お団子可愛いでしょう？ 見てー！
Eheh, the hair buns are cute, right? Look!
毛量がめちゃめちゃあるんです、ロボ子
Roboko has so much hair volume!
後ろから見るとすごいね
Looking from behind, it's incredible.
ブブブブブブブ...
Bzzzzzz...
全部可愛い
Everything is cute.
やったー！ オールパーフェクトじゃん！
Yay! That means all perfect!
パーフェクト
Perfect.
はるちゃん、これ途中でやってたの気づいた？
Haru-chan, did you notice I was doing this during the song?
これ？ 歌中？ やってた。気づいた
This? During the song? You were doing it. I noticed.
なんか、こっち見てやってたよね？
You were looking right over here while doing it, right?
「気づけー」って。キメキメでやってたから
Like "Notice me!" You were striking full poses!
あー、というわけで...
Ah, anyway...
おめでとう、本当に。改めて
Congratulations, truly. Once again.
なんかすごい丁寧に言ってくれるからさ
You say it so politely and thoughtfully.
おめでたいんだもん
Because it's something worth celebrating.
えー、嬉しい！ ありがとう！
Aww, I'm so happy! Thank you!
次も... まだ早いか。いいよ、大丈夫
Next up... Or is it too early? It's fine, no worries.
え、まだね、いっぱいあると思うからね、頑張ってね
There's still plenty left to come, so do your best!
頑張る！
I will!
はるちゃん、じゃあ応援してね
Haru-chan, cheer for me then!
応援する。見てるね
I'll cheer for you. I'll be watching.
見てて！ ありがとう！
Watch me! Thank you!
バイバイ、はるちゃん！ またね！
Bye-bye, Haru-chan! See you!
ありがとう、バイバイ
Thank you, bye-bye.
はるちゃんって結構マイペースなんですよ
Haru-chan is really easygoing and goes at her own pace.
どいつもこいつもなんだかやっぱノーテンキ
Everyone seems so carefree after all.
キルのお団子 悩みはきっとあるでしょう
In these bun hairdos, surely there are worries too.
雑多で半端な憂鬱とも無縁
Unbothered by crude, half-baked gloom.
同じ頭の中はぐちゃぐちゃさ
Inside our similar heads, it's a complete mess.
お前が行く気がないの 法定停止
You've got no spine, legal standstill.
いけない いけない事柄なんてないから
Because there's no such thing as something off-limits.
イヤイヤ三振 じゃんけんでさあお行き
Reluctant strikeout, off you go with rock-paper-scissors.
有料地獄で手厚く召されてく
Cordially summoned to a paid hell.
君はもう ハイスピードだな
You're already moving at high speed.
邪魔 邪魔 終わらせちゃって
Get out of the way, get out of the way, wrap it up.
派手でめっちゃなドラマ
Such a flashy and chaotic drama.
ちゃんと願いを叶えよ
Grant my wish properly now.
いい いい 許婚っきゅん I love you なのさ 四六時中 愛をちょうだい
Yes, yes, betrothed darling, I love you! Give me love 24/7!
待った！
Wait!
いい いい いいのかっきゅん 愛 愛 愛はなノックアウト 一分の一秒も待たない
Is it okay, darling? Love, love, love is a knockout! I won't wait even a millisecond!
それでも結局見えないあいつの胸の内
But in the end, I still can't see into that guy's heart.
お邪魔虫なら仲間外れもいらないから
If you're an intruder, no need to leave me out either.
先輩後輩演技者関係ない
Seniors, juniors, actors—none of that matters.
いざ尋常に勝負
Now, let's fight fair and square!
君ももしもその気なら Boy meets girl が始まりそうなら
If you're up for it too, if a "boy meets girl" story is about to start...
まだ見ぬ技作り出す 僕ら手放そう スイートだな
We'll create unseen moves! Let's let go, how sweet!
誰がどう見ても同じだね
No matter who looks at it, it's the same, isn't it?
平常心な修羅場
A carnage faced with a calm mind.
ちゃんと願いを叶えよ
Grant my wish properly now.
意味深なら両愛 曖昧な愛よりチョキチョキ
If it's meaningful, it's mutual love. Scissors over vague love.
四の五の言わず察して頂戴
Stop making excuses and get the hint, please!
待った！
Wait!
一ミリの電磁波 鼻血が出そうだ
One millimeter of electromagnetic waves, I might get a nosebleed.
自分の意思をどうのこうのちょうだい
Give me your own opinion or whatever!
いい いい 許婚っきゅん I love you なのさ 四六時中 愛をちょうだい
Yes, yes, betrothed darling, I love you! Give me love 24/7!
待った！
Wait!
いい いい いいのかっきゅん 愛 愛 愛はなノックアウト 一分の一秒も待たない
Is it okay, darling? Love, love, love is a knockout! I won't wait even a millisecond!
これだって知る愛 たいしたことないかも知れん 毎晩競ってんだ 足りないや
The love I know might be no big deal after all. Competing every night, it's never enough.
偶然？必然？ご縁？ご恩？修羅場 平穏無情 免許改定
Coincidence? Fate? Destiny? Gratitude? Carnage? Calmness without mercy, license revised.
はい、というわけで「許婚っきゅん」でしたー！
Yes, and that was "Iinazukyun"!
どうでしたか〜？
How was it?
え、シルエットのさ、ここ格好良くなかった？
Eh, wasn't this part with the silhouettes so cool?
ポンポンってしてんの
The part where they went like "pop, pop"?
結構お気に入りポイントです！
That's one of my favorite parts!
はい！どうだった？
Alright! How was it?
可愛いでしょう！改めて新衣装！
Isn't it cute? Once again, my new outfit!
ねー！ミドリーとモホるちゃんともね、歌えて嬉しい！
Right? I'm so happy to sing with Midori and Mohoru-chan too!
まさかの「え〜！？」って思ってる人もね、めっちゃ多かったと思うんだけど
I think a lot of people were like, "Eh, really?!"
お呼びしました、今回は！嬉しいです！
But I invited them this time! I'm so glad!
さあ、というわけで
Well then, with that said...
もう結構歌ったね〜
I've already sung quite a lot, haven't I?
なんかそろそろウズウズしてる人たちがいっぱいいる気がするの！
I feel like there are a lot of people getting itchingly eager by now!
ウズウズウズウズウズウズウズ！
Itchingly, itchingly, itchingly eager!
僕が一番ウズウズしてる！
I'm the one who's most eager!
はい！というわけで、待てができないので
Alright! So, since I can't wait any longer...
ご紹介したいと思います！
I'd like to introduce them!
誕生日と言えばー？
Speaking of birthdays...?
誕生日グッズー！
Birthday merchandise!
今回の誕生日グッズはこちらー！
Here is this time's birthday merch!
はい、久々にタペストリーを出します！
Yes, I'm releasing a tapestry after a long time!
まず1つ目！B2タペストリー！
First up! A B2 tapestry!
こちらイラストはね、とってもクールな僕なんですけれども
The illustration here features a super cool me,
SYAGAMU先生に描いていただきましたー！
drawn by SYAGAMU-sensei!
あ、これ「竜違い」とかやめてね！
Ah, don't say "wrong dragon" or anything, okay!
竜！
It's a dragon!
前のも好きだし、お前も好きだぞ！みんな愛してる竜です！
"I liked the previous one, but I like you too! I love everyone" kind of dragon!
めっちゃ格好良いよね！
It's so cool, right?
強そうな竜と強そうな僕！
A tough-looking dragon and a tough-looking me!
格好良いでしょう？
Pretty cool, isn't it?
そして2つ目はー？
And the second item is...?
なんと！お腹いっぱい食べちゃう餃子皿ー！
Amazingly, "Eat Your Fill Gyoza Plate!"
なんと！
Amazingly...
こちらロボ子先生が描いてくれましたー！
Roboco-sensei drew this illustration!
もー食べる気満々の 沼にハマってるロボ子とロボさー
Roboco and Robosa, ready to eat and stuck in a swamp...
めちゃめちゃ可愛いでしょ！
It's super cute, right?
このお皿使っていっぱいね 餃子なり何なり食べてください！
Use this plate to eat lots of dumplings or whatever else!
お腹いっぱいになると幸せになるのでね！
Eating until you're full makes you happy!
はい！そして次は？
Alright! And next is...
ご飯をたべたら喉も渇く！「ちあーず！グラス」ですね！
After eating, you get thirsty! The "Cheers! Glass"!
ビール入れてもいいし、お茶入れたっていいし、ジュース入れたっていい！
You can pour beer, tea, or juice in it!
美味しいもの どんどん行きましょう！
Enjoy all your favorite drinks!
こちらもなんと、ロボ子先生が描いてくれました！
This one was drawn by Roboco-sensei too!
可愛すぎる！こんなウィンクされたらいっぱい飲んじゃうってね！
So cute! A wink like this makes you want to drink a lot!
いいですから！是非、ご飯と飲み物…
It's great! Please, for your food and drinks...
食卓にお使いくださいまし！
...use them at your dining table!
今度僕も配信で使ってみようと思うので、是非チェックしてみてください！
I'm planning to use them on stream soon, so please check them out!
そしてまだまだあります！こちら、ドン！
And there's still more! Here it is, boom!
はい！僕の大好きなぬいぐるみー！
Yes! My beloved plushie!
本日も可愛いものが出来ましたー！
We made something super cute again!
見て！お座りしてんだ！今回のお座りぬいぐるみ！ちゃんとロボサーもね、ここにいますよー！
Look! It's sitting down! This sitting plushie has Robosa right here too!
はい！
Yes!
今回はお座りのぬいぐるみなので、そのままお部屋に飾ってもいいし、お出かけでもね、一緒に写真撮りやすいのかなと思います！
Since it's a sitting plushie, you can display it in your room, or easily take photos with it on outings!
はい！いっぱい色んなところに連れて行ってあげてください！
Yes! Please take it with you to lots of different places!
大切にしてね！無くさないでね！置いていかないでね！
Take good care of it! Don't lose it or leave it behind!
たくさん買ってたっていいんだからねー！
Buying a whole lot of them is totally fine too!
そして！ボイスも出ます！
And! Voice packs are coming out too!
今回は、「僕 vs りゅう」！
This time, it's "Me vs Dragon"!
マジでりゅうの名前定まらんのよ！緑だっていいし、龍だっていいし、ドラゴン君だっていい！
Honestly, the dragon's name isn't set! Midori, Ryu, Dragon-kun, anything goes!
なんだったっていい！うん、いいよね！
Anything works! Yeah, it's fine, right?
きみに襲い掛かる龍に可愛さ勝負を挑む僕のお話し！
A story about me challenging a dragon that attacks you to a cuteness battle!
はい、どんなお話しかは是非買って聴いてみてください！
Please buy and listen to find out what kind of story it is!
さあ最後はこちら！
Now, lastly, this!
はい、今回のフルセット購入特典についてお話しします！
Yes, I'll talk about the full-set purchase bonus!
まず1つ目！数量限定版が今回は…あります！
First off, the limited quantity version is available this time!
数量限定版は、僕の直筆サインと、箔押し複製メッセージ入りのポストカードになります！
The limited version comes with a postcard featuring my handwritten signature and a foil-stamped message!
今回は僕のこの配信が終わったと同時にカートがオープンしますので…
The cart opens as soon as this stream ends...
そのタイミングで是非狙ってみてください！スタートダッシュの準備は…いいかー？
...so be sure to aim for that timing! Are you ready for the start dash?
是非ゲットしてくださいね！
Please be sure to get it!
もちろん通常版もあります！直筆サインはないんですけど、箔押し入りのサインとメッセージのポストカードがついてきます！
Of course, there's a regular version too! It has a postcard with a foil-stamped signature and message!
そして！まだフルセット購入特典には、ボイスがつきます！
And the full-set purchase bonus also includes bonus voice tracks!
「きみと、りゅうと、よるのそら」！販売ボイスの少し後の時間帯のお話しで、時間軸が続いております！
"You, Dragon, and the Night Sky"! It continues the timeline right after the main voice pack!
特典ボイスも合わせると「あの後の続きがあるの？」って楽しめるので是非聴いてほしいです！
Listening to the bonus voice reveals what happens next, so please check it out! It's fun!
そしてなんと！「hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME」で使用できるカードが1枚ついてきます！
And amazingly! You get 1 card usable in the "hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME"!
同梱するカードは「ホロライブプロダクション オフィシャルショップ」で購入されたお客様のみの対象となります！
The card is exclusively for purchases made at the hololive production OFFICIAL SHOP!
今回特典につくのは、ゲームで1枚だけ使用でき、推しをアピールすることができる「推しホロメンカード」です！
It's an "Oshi Holomen Card"—a card you can use 1 copy of to show off your favorite VTuber!
みんな欲しいでしょ、これ！今しか買えない！ロボサーは買うべき！強いよー！
Everyone wants this, right?! It's limited! Robosa should get it—it's strong!
カードの詳細や遊び方は、「hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME」の公式ホームページで確認してみてください！
For card details and rules, please check the hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME website!
同梱するカードは日本語版のみとなりますのでご了承ください！No English, sorry!
Please note that the included card is in Japanese only! No English, sorry!
グッズのカートオープンは、配信終了後になります！みんな待機して買ってねー！
The goods cart opens after the stream! Stay tuned and get yours! Feel free to buy a lot!
そして！
And!
この後はなんと！
After this, guess what?!
実は初めての...
Actually, for the first time...
アンコールライブがあります！
We're having an encore live performance!
酒はどんだけでも飲まれるな！
No matter how much booze there is, don't let it get to you!
最近お酒飲んでない！
I haven't been drinking lately!
アンコールとアルコール似てるんだわ
"Encore" and "alcohol" sound so similar.
はい、というわけで なんと今回はね アンコールライブがありますので
So anyway, since we have an encore live this time,
アンコールライブもね みんながずっとボクに歌ってほしそうだったあの曲を歌っちゃおうかなと思っているので
for the encore, I'm thinking of singing that song everyone seemed to want me to sing for a while,
楽しみにしててくださーい！
so please look forward to it!
なんかせっかくだからね 写真撮影会とかね
Since we're doing this, like a photo shoot time or something,
ロボさーと密な空間で いっぱい見せちゃおうかなって思っていまーす
I'm thinking of showing you guys lots of things up close together with Robosa!
あ！メンバーのプレゼントもありがとうね！みんな ぜひ見ててくださーい！
Ah! Thanks for the membership gifts too! Everyone, please check it out!
はい というわけで
All right, so...
ロボさー
Robosa...
早いけど
It's early, but...
次が最後の曲になっちゃうみたいです
it looks like the next one will be the last song.
ボクはもう9歳...
I'm already 9 years old...
9歳になって ロボさー ここまで成長を見届けてくれてありがとうね
Turning 9 years old... Robosa, thank you for watching me grow this far.
これからもまだまだボクは成長していくので
I'm going to keep growing more and more from now on,
一緒に末永く楽しんでいきましょう！
so let's keep enjoying things together for a long, long time!
最後の曲は...
The last song...
初めにちらっと言っていたけど
As I hinted a bit at the start...
ドラゴンくんに乗りたいな〜
I want to ride Dragon-kun~
一緒に頑張ってくれる？
Will you work hard together with me?
ね、ドラゴンくん？
Right, Dragon-kun?
DAN DAN 心魅かれてく その眩しい笑顔に
Bit by bit, my heart is drawn to that dazzling smile of yours.
果てない闇から飛び出そう
Let's break out of the endless darkness,
Hold my hand
君と出会ったとき
When I first met you,
子供の頃大切に
I remembered the place
思っていた場所を思い出したんだ
I held dear back when I was a child.
僕と踊ってくれないか
Won't you dance with me?
光と影の Winding road
On this winding road of light and shadow,
今でもあいつに夢中なの？
are you still crazy about him even now?
少しだけ振り返りたくなる
Though there are times
ようなときもあるけど
when I feel like looking back a little,
愛と勇気と誇りを持って
with love, courage, and pride,
戦うよ
I will fight.
DAN DAN 心魅かれてく
Bit by bit, my heart is drawn to you,
この星の希望の欠片
the fragments of hope on this planet.
きっと誰しもが永遠を手に入れたい
Surely everyone wants to gain eternity.
全然気にしない振りしても
Even if I pretend not to care at all,
ほら君に恋してる
look, I'm in love with you.
果てない闇から飛び出そう
Let's break out of the endless darkness,
Hold your hand
怒った顔も疲れてる君も好きだけど
I love you even when you're angry or tired, but
あんなに飛ばして生きて大丈夫かなと思う
I wonder if you'll be okay living life at such a breakneck pace.
僕は何気ない仕草に
I'm being swung around by your casual gestures,
振り回されてる Seaside blue
in this seaside blue.
それでもあいつに夢中なの？
Even so, are you still crazy about him?
もっと聞きたいことがあったのに
Even though there was so much more I wanted to ask,
二人の会話が
our conversation
車の音に阻まれて
gets drowned out by the noise of cars
通りに舞うよ
and dances down the street.
DAN DAN 心魅かれてく
Bit by bit, my heart is drawn to you.
自分でも不思議なんだけど
It's strange even to me, but
何かあるとすぐに
whenever something happens,
君に電話したくなる
I immediately want to call you.
全然気のない振りしても
Even if I pretend to have no interest at all...
結局君のことだけ見てた
In the end, all I ever do is look at you
海の彼方へ 飛び出そうよ
Let's leap out beyond the sea
Hold my hand
おっとっとっと...
Whoa-whoa-whoa...
みんなー！
Everyone!
ロボ子さー！
It's Roboko-sa!
今日は見に来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you so much for watching today!
この後はなんとー！
Coming up next...
メンバー限定ルームで歌いまーす！
I'll be singing in the members-only stream!
遊びに来てねー！
Please come join me!
グッズもめっちゃ可愛ちいから
The merch is super cute too,
ゲットしてくれよなー！
so make sure to get yours!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
なんか君も遅いね ドラゴンくん
Looks like you're slow too, Mr. Dragon.